purina.com 2019-12-26

# Privacy Policy

### **SCOPE OF THIS  NOTICE**

Please read this privacy notice (“ **Notice** ”) carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your Personal Data and how we will treat it. This Notice applies to individuals who interact with _Nestlé_ services as consumers (“ **you** ”). This Notice explains how your Personal Data is collected, used, and disclosed by Nestlé Purina PetCare Company, a U.S. corporation, and its subsidiaries including Petfinder.com and also includes third parties acting on our behalf (collectively " ** _Nestlé_** ", " **We** ", " **Us** "). It also tells you how you can access and update your Personal Data and make certain choices about how your Personal Data are used.

This Notice covers both our online and offline data collection activities, including Personal Data that We collect through our various channels such as websites, apps, third party social networks, Office of Consumer Affairs, points of sale and events where this policy is provided to you. Please note that We might combine personal data from different sources (website, offline event). As part of this, We combine Personal Data that were originally collected by different _Nestlé_ entities or _Nestlé_ partners. We may combine information from third parties with information We already have.

If you do not provide necessary Personal Data to Us (We will indicate to you when this is the case, for example, by providing this information in our registration forms), We may not be able to provide you with certain goods and/or services. 

* * *

### **1\. PERSONAL DATA THAT WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

We collect various types of information from you, as described below.

**Personal contact information**. This includes any information you provide to Us that would allow Us to contact you, such as your name, postal address, e-mail address, social network details, or phone number. 

**Account login information**. _ _ Any information that is required to give you access to your specific account profile. Examples include your login ID/email address, screen name, password in unrecoverable form, and/or security question and answer.

**Demographic information & interests**. _ _ Any information that describes your demographic or behavioral characteristics. Examples include your date of birth, age or age range, gender, geographic location (e.g. zip code), favorite products, hobbies and interests, and household or lifestyle information. This may include information about your health, medical conditions, nutrition, and exercise habits and goals. It may include information about your children’s genders, feeding styles, birthdates, or expected due dates. It may include information about work status, professional credentials. It may include  information when you inquire about adopting a pet through a Petfinder member adoption organization, or create a saved pet search alert.  In some cases, this could include information that you give Us about someone else. For example, if you provide a friend’s email address for a tell-a-friend program. It may also include information about your pets and pet preferences. If you are a health care professional, We may collect information about your practice. 

**Information from computer/mobile device**. _ _ Any information about the computer system or other technological device that you use to access one of our websites or apps, such as the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer or device to the Internet, operating system type, and web browser type and version. If you access a _Nestlé_ website or app via a mobile device such as a smartphone, the collected information will also include, where permitted, your phone’s unique device ID, advertising ID, geo-location, and other similar mobile device data.

**Websites/communication usage information**. _ _ As you navigate through and interact with our websites/apps or emails, We use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your actions. This includes information such as which links you click on, which pages or content you view and for how long, and other similar information and statistics about your interactions, such as content response times, download errors and length of visits to certain pages. This information is captured using automated technologies such as cookies and web beacons and is also collected through the use of third party tracking for analytics and advertising purposes. 

**Market research & consumer feedback.** _ _ Any information that you share with Us about your experience of using our products and services.

**Consumer-generated content.**  Any content that you create and then share with Us on third party social networks or by uploading it to one of our websites or apps, including the use of third party social network apps such as Facebook. Examples include photos, videos, personal stories, or other similar media or content. Where permitted, We collect and publish consumer-generated content in connection with a variety of activities, including contests and other promotions, website community features, consumer engagement, and third-party social networking.

**Third party social network information**. Any information that you share publicly on a third-party social network or information that is part of your profile on a third-party social network (such as Facebook) and that you allow the third-party social network to share with Us. Examples include your basic account information (e.g. name, email address, gender, birthday, current city, profile picture, user ID, list of friends, etc.) and any other additional information or activities that you permit the third-party social network to share. We receive your third party social network profile information (or parts of it) every time you download or interact with a _Nestlé_ web application on a third party social network such as Facebook, every time you use a social networking feature that is integrated within a _Nestlé_ site (such as Facebook Connect) or every time you interact with Us through a third party social network. To learn more about how your information from a third-party social network is obtained by _Nestlé_ , or to opt out of sharing such social network information, please visit the website of the relevant third-party social network.

**Payment and Financial information**. Any information that We need in order to fulfill an order, or that you use to make a purchase, such as your debit or credit card details (cardholder name, card number, expiration date, etc.) or other forms of payment (if such are made available). In any case, We or our payment processing provider(s) handle payment and financial information in a manner compliant with applicable laws, regulations and security standards such as PCI DSS.

* * *

### **2\. HOW WE COLLECT PERSONAL DATA ABOUT YOU**

**We collect information directly from you** **.** __ For example, We collect information when you place an order with us. We collect information when you register on one of our websites or apps. We collect information when you become a member of a loyalty program. We collect information when you sign up for our emails. We collect information from printed or digital registrations and similar forms that We collect via, for example, postal mail, in-store demos, contests, and other promotions or events. We collect information when you inquire about adopting a pet through a Petfinder member adoption organization, or create a saved pet search alert. We collect information if you fill out a survey or use other tools on your websites or apps. We also collect information if you contact Us through our websites or apps, via email or through social media.

**We collect information from you passively**. For example, We use tracking tools like browser cookies and web beacons. We do this on our websites and in emails that We send to you. We collect information about users over time when you use this website. This includes usage and browser information. We may have third parties collect information this way. We also collect information from our mobile apps. 

**We get information about you from other sources.** For example, our affiliates and business partners may give Us information about you. We may receive information from companies who compile information about shoppers and their preferences. Social media platforms may also give Us information about you. We may get information about your interactions with our ads on third-party sites.

* * *

### **3\. PERSONAL DATA OF CHILDREN**

We do not knowingly solicit or collect personal data from children below the age of 13. If you are a parent or legal guardian and think that your child under 13 has given Us information, you can contact Us in writing or by email as provided below under the section titled CONTACT. Please mark your inquiries "COPPA Information Request." You can learn more about how to protect children’s privacy online by visiting the Federal Trade Commission's webpage, [Protecting Your Child’s Privacy Online](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online).

* * *

### **4\. USES MADE OF YOUR  PERSONAL DATA**

The following paragraphs describe the various purposes for which We collect and use your Personal Data, and the different types of Personal Data that are collected for each purpose. Please note that not all of the uses below will be relevant to every individual.

**Consumer service**. _ _ We use your Personal Data for consumer service purposes, including responding to your inquiries. This typically requires the use of certain personal contact information and information regarding the reason for your inquiry (e.g. order status, technical issue, product question/complaint, general question, etc.). 

**Contests, marketing and other promotions**. _ _ We may use your Personal Data to provide you with information about goods or services (e.g. marketing communications or campaigns or promotions). This can be done via means such as email, ads, SMS, phone calls and postal mailings to the extent permitted by applicable laws. On occasion, these communications may also introduce you to other affiliated brands and partners and inform you about products, services, offers, and promotions from other companies and organizations. Some of our campaigns and promotions are run on third party websites and/or social networks. For more information about our contests and other promotions, please see the official rules or details posted with each contest/promotion.  We may use your friend’s email address to send them information you request through a “tell-a-friend” feature.

**Third party social networks:**  We use your Personal Data when you interact with third party social networking features, such as "Like" functions, to serve you with advertisements and engage with you on third party social networks. You can learn more about how these features work, the profile data that We obtain about you, and find out how to opt out by reviewing the privacy notices of the relevant third-party social networks.

**Personalization**. With your consent (where required), We may use your Personal Data (i) to analyze your preferences and habits, (ii) to anticipate your needs based on our analysis of your profile, (iii) to improve and personalize your experience on our websites and apps; (iv) to ensure that content from our websites/apps is optimized for you and for your computer or device; (v) to provide you with targeted advertising and content, and (vi) to allow you to participate in interactive features, when you choose to do so. For example, We remember your login ID/email address or screen name so that you can quickly login the next time you visit our site or so that you can easily retrieve the items you previously placed in your shopping cart. Based on this type of information, and with your consent (where required), We also show you specific _Nestlé_ content or promotions that are tailored to your interests. 

**Order fulfillment**. We use your Personal Data to process and ship your orders, inform you about the status of your orders, correct addresses and conduct identity verification and other fraud detection activities. This involves the use of certain Personal Data and payment information.

**Other general purposes (e.g. internal or market research, analytic, security)**. In accordance with applicable laws, We use your Personal Data for other general business purposes, such as maintaining your account, conducting internal or market research and measuring the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. We reserve the right, if you have _Nestlé_ accounts, to reconcile those accounts into one single account. We also use your Personal Data for management and operation of our communications, IT and security systems.

* * *

### **5\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

**The** **Nestlé S.A. family of companies.** We share information within the Nestlé S.A. family of companies, which includes all direct and indirect subsidiaries of parent company Nestlé S.A.

**Service providers** **.** These are external companies that We use to help Us run our business (e.g. order fulfillment, payment processing, fraud detection and identity verification, website operation, market research companies, support services, promotions, website development, data analysis, CRC, etc.). 

**Credit reporting agencies/debt collectors** **.** To the extent permitted by applicable law, credit reporting agencies and debt collectors are external companies that We use to help Us to verify your creditworthiness (in particular for orders with invoice) or to collect outstanding invoices.

**Third party companies using Personal Data for their own purposes** **.**  We may share information with third parties. This information may be used by third parties for their own purposes, including pet adoption organizations to help facilitate pet adoptions. This may include their own marketing purposes. They may send or provide you with offers for products or services that may interest you. We may also permit third parties to collect information about you on our websites or apps for their own purposes.

**Sharing Personal Data for legal reasons or due to merger/acquisition** **.**  In the event that _Nestlé_ or its assets are acquired by, or merged with, another company including through bankruptcy, We will share your Personal Data with any of our legal successors. We will also disclose your Personal Data to third parties (i) when required by applicable law; (ii) in response to legal proceedings; (iii) in response to a request from a competent law enforcement agency; (iv) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, or the public; or (v) to enforce the terms of any agreement or the terms of our website.

* * *

### **6\. DATA PROTECTION AND RETENTION**

**We use reasonable and appropriate security measures as required by applicable law**. The transmission of information via the Internet is, unfortunately, not completely secure and despite our efforts to protect your Personal Data, We cannot guarantee the security of the data during transmission through our websites/apps. **** It is important that you also play a role in keeping your Personal Data safe and secure. When signing up for an online account, please be sure to choose an account password that would be difficult for others to guess and never reveal your password to anyone else. You are responsible for keeping this password confidential and for any use of your account. If you use a shared or public computer, never choose to have your login ID/email address or password remembered and make sure to log out of your account every time you leave the computer. You should also make use of any privacy settings or controls We provide you in our websites/apps.

**Retention of Personal Data**. We keep Personal Data as long as it is necessary or relevant for the practices described in this Notice. We also keep Personal Data as otherwise required by law. 

* * *

### **7\. YOUR CHOICES ABOUT HOW WE USE AND DISCLOSE YOUR  PERSONAL DATA**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the Personal Data that you provide to Us. The following mechanisms give you the following control over your Personal Data:

**Advertising, marketing and promotions** **.**   You can opt out of marketing emails by following the instructions provided in each such communication. Please note that even if you opt out from receiving marketing communications, you will still receive administrative communications from Us, such as order or other transaction confirmations, notifications about your account activities (e.g. account confirmations, password changes, confirmation of pet adoption inquiry and submission, etc.), and other important non-marketing related announcements.

**Cookies, Tracking Tools, and Targeted Advertising.** To learn how to manage how We and our vendors use cookies and other tracking tools, and to read our **Do Not Track Policy** , please click About Our Ads.

* * *

### **8\. THIRD PARTY WEBSITES AND SERVICES**

We may link to third party websites or apps, including social media platforms. Our websites or apps may also include third party content that collects information. This includes information collected by cookies, pixels, or other tracking tools. We do not control these third parties or their tracking tools. This policy does not apply to the privacy practices of these third-party websites or apps. Please read the privacy policies of other websites and apps carefully. We are not responsible for the practices of these third-party websites or apps.

* * *

### **9\. YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

If you are a California resident, you may have the right to request and receive certain information about our disclosure of your personal information to third parties for their own marketing use, and your choices with respect to such disclosures. To request this information please contact Us in writing or by email as provided below under the section titled CONTACT.  Please mark your inquiries “California Privacy Rights Request.”

* * *

### **10\. CHANGES TO THIS  NOTICE**

If We change the way We handle your Personal Data, We will update this Notice. We reserve the right to make changes to our practices and this Notice at any time, please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our Notice.

* * *

### **11.** ** ** **CONTACT**

To ask questions or make comments on this Notice and our privacy practices, please contact Us by email at: CustomerService@purina.nestle.com or call our Office of Consumer Affairs at 1.800.778.7462 or write to Us at 

Nestlé Purina PetCare    
P.O. Box 340   
Neenah WI 54957.
